<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="wl_vpc">
  
    <copyright>
    If not stated otherwise in this file or this component's Licenses.txt file the
    following copyright and licenses apply:

    Copyright 2016 RDK Management

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
    -------
    Copyright © 2008-2011 Kristian Høgsberg
    Copyright © 2010-2011 Intel Corporation
    Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
    software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
    without fee, provided that\n the above copyright notice appear in
    all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
    notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
    the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
    pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
    written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
    representations about the suitability of this software for any
    purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
    warranty.
    THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
    SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
    FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
    SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
    WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
    AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION,
    ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF
    THIS SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>
  <interface name="wl_vpc" version="1">
    
    <description summary="Video path control">
      The video path control protocol provides a mechanism for the compositor and client to
      cooperate in the control of the decoding path used for video.  The compositor can
      request the client to use a fully accelerated hardware path or a video-as-graphics
      path.
    </description>
    
    <request name="get_vpc_surface">
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="wl_vpc_surface"/>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
    </request>
    
  </interface>

  <interface name="wl_vpc_surface" version="2">

    <description summary="vpc surface">
    An interface that may be implemented by a wl_surface which is being used to
    present video which allows the compositor to control the decoding pathway
    being used for the video and to adjust its positioning.
    </description>

    <enum name="pathway">
      <entry name="unspecified" value="0"/>
      <entry name="hardware" value="1"/>
      <entry name="graphics" value="2"/>
    </enum>

    <enum name="crop">
      <entry name="denom" value="100000"/>
    </enum>

    <event name="video_path_change">
      <arg name="new_pathway" type="uint"/>
    </event>

    <event name="video_xform_change">
      <arg name="x_translation" type="int" summary="x-axis translation"/>
      <arg name="y_translation" type="int" summary="y-axis translation"/>
      <arg name="x_scale_num" type="uint"  summary="x scale factor numerator"/>
      <arg name="x_scale_denom" type="uint"  summary="x scale factor denominator"/>
      <arg name="y_scale_num" type="uint"  summary="y scale factor numerator"/>
      <arg name="y_scale_denom" type="uint"  summary="y scale factor denominator"/>
      <arg name="output_width" type="uint" summary="width of associated output"/>
      <arg name="output_height" type="uint" summary="height of associated output"/>
    </event>

    <request name="set_geometry">
      <arg name="x" type="int"/>
      <arg name="y" type="int"/>
      <arg name="width" type="int"/>
      <arg name="height" type="int"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_geometry_with_crop" since="2">
      <description summary="set geometry with crop">
      Set vpc surface geometry with the ability to crop
      the frame.  The x, y, width, and heigth are values in
      screen coordinates that specify the rectangle to
      be textured with the video frame.  The crop values, when
      divided by crop denom give the region of the frame to
      use as the texture.
      </description>
      <arg name="x" type="int"/>
      <arg name="y" type="int"/>
      <arg name="width" type="int"/>
      <arg name="height" type="int"/>
      <arg name="crop_x" type="int"/>
      <arg name="crop_y" type="int"/>
      <arg name="crop_width" type="int"/>
      <arg name="crop_height" type="int"/>
    </request>

  </interface>

</protocol>

